<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="https://www.praj.in" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><title>Priyadarshi Raj</title><link>https://www.praj.in</link><description>I'm a computer science undergrad and a passionate software craftsman</description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 21:42:24 +0530</lastBuildDate><generator>clj-rss</generator><item><guid>https://www.praj.in/posts/2020/graalvms-secret-llvm-backend/</guid><link>https://www.praj.in/posts/2020/graalvms-secret-llvm-backend/</link><title>GraalVM's secret LLVM backend</title><description>You might have come across GraalVM's LLVM interpreter lli but did you know that it can also output LLVM bitcode too? Welp, maybe it isn't a secret anymore but GraalVM has an experimental backend that can build native images using LLVM instead of Graal. Let's have a quick demo. </description><pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://www.praj.in/posts/2020/calling-uname-from-java-using-graalvm/</guid><link>https://www.praj.in/posts/2020/calling-uname-from-java-using-graalvm/</link><title>Calling uname from Java using GraalVM</title><description>For years I'd been searching how to build native Linux apps using Java and somehow GraalVM has concluded it all. GraalVM's native-image tooling is arguably the most elegant way of connecting Java to the native world. We'll be exploring a clean way to interoperate with C libraries by writing a uname alternative in pure Java. No JNI mess, no sun.misc.Unsafe imports, just GraalVM. 🛠️ </description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://www.praj.in/posts/2020/zimbra-mailbot-update-1/</guid><link>https://www.praj.in/posts/2020/zimbra-mailbot-update-1/</link><title>Zimbra Mailbot: Update 1</title><description>My college exclusively uses Zimbra 8 as its mail server and the most annoying part is that there's no easy way to fetch new emails automatically (unlike Gmail app). The unavailability of any official Android app only makes it worse. So it's been a while since I started working on this chatbot that can forward emails from any Zimbra account to Telegram. On a side note, it's also helping me sharpen my Clojure skills for web dev. </description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://www.praj.in/posts/2020/self-contained-native-looking-apps/</guid><link>https://www.praj.in/posts/2020/self-contained-native-looking-apps/</link><title>Self-contained, native-looking apps with SWT and ModiTect</title><description>The Standard Widget Toolkit, commonly known as SWT, is one of the few Java GUI libraries that are still actively maintained. Popularized by the use in Eclipse IDEs, it has a remarkable ability to present apps that look and feel native across all major desktops. Let me show you how to set up a Gradle project to build cross-platform, self-contained apps that mimic the native theme. 🤖 </description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://www.praj.in/posts/2020/making-standalone-java-apps/</guid><link>https://www.praj.in/posts/2020/making-standalone-java-apps/</link><title>Making Standalone Java apps</title><description>Back in high school days, I learned how Java programs could work flawlessly across different machines without the need for any additional compilation - Write once, run anywhere. One of our laptops had a 64-bit Ubuntu installed while the other one had a 32-bit Windows 7. I tested out on a few more platforms and realized one particular hurdle that constantly popped up: It was necessary to have Java installed beforehand, which most OSs didn't ship by default. So here's a post about how you could make your apps truly standalone. </description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://www.praj.in/posts/2020/opengl-demo-using-graalvm/</guid><link>https://www.praj.in/posts/2020/opengl-demo-using-graalvm/</link><title>OpenGL demo using GraalVM</title><description>Let me show how you can use GraalVM to create an OpenGL app in Java. This is made possible by the native-image tool that helps GraalVM produce truly native binaries capable of interacting with native libraries directly, without any JNI overhead. ⚡️ </description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://www.praj.in/posts/2020/the-season-of-lockdowns/</guid><link>https://www.praj.in/posts/2020/the-season-of-lockdowns/</link><title>The Season of Lockdowns</title><description>We all expect a bunch of new stories, resolutions, and ideas popping up at the start of each year. But 2020 wasn't supposed to be just another year, it's a new decade. So it's natural to expect that the usual new year excitement would be amped up all round the world. Alas, things turned out in an exactly opposite way, isn't it? </description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://www.praj.in/posts/2019/gsoc-2019-week-12-updates/</guid><link>https://www.praj.in/posts/2019/gsoc-2019-week-12-updates/</link><title>GSoC 2019: Week 12 updates</title><description>Finally, we're at the end! This last week of GSoC includes implementation of parts of the revised Package Manager model, namely the PackageDatabase and some methods for interacting with our Jenkins repository. </description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://www.praj.in/posts/2019/gsoc-2019-week-11-updates/</guid><link>https://www.praj.in/posts/2019/gsoc-2019-week-11-updates/</link><title>GSoC 2019: Week 11 updates</title><description>The penultimate week of GSoC was filled with architectural designs and discussions. I've spent a good amount of time researching on apt, pacman and npm, and along with the lessons learned from the previous Package Manager implementation, we're planning out an improved design for making the Package Manager more extensible and robust. </description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://www.praj.in/posts/2019/gsoc-2019-week-10-updates/</guid><link>https://www.praj.in/posts/2019/gsoc-2019-week-10-updates/</link><title>GSoC 2019: Week 10 updates</title><description>Alright! The last month is half done, and this week brings some more updates to the Package Manager. The integration is ready to be tested and is almost working just the way it used to, along with the invisible Package Manager underneath. Though it only supports storing and loading of cache now, future PRs should bring full powers to it: installation, uninstallation, etc. </description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://www.praj.in/posts/2019/gsoc-2019-week-9-updates/</guid><link>https://www.praj.in/posts/2019/gsoc-2019-week-9-updates/</link><title>GSoC 2019: Week 9 updates</title><description>So the first week of our third phase, finally came to an end. Almost the entire week was dedicated to the package manager, and it's still far from being complete. But the launcher no longer crashes or freezes while starting up with it, and that's a relieving thing to see. </description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://www.praj.in/posts/2019/gsoc-2019-week-8-updates/</guid><link>https://www.praj.in/posts/2019/gsoc-2019-week-8-updates/</link><title>GSoC 2019: Week 8 updates</title><description>This was quite a terrible week for me. I had to be inactive because of some serious, untimely issues. I also had to shift to my college's city, as classes were about to restart. So there's no contribution to show in this update. I'll try to make up for the lost time in the upcoming week and take care of the package manager. </description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://www.praj.in/posts/2019/gsoc-2019-week-7-updates/</guid><link>https://www.praj.in/posts/2019/gsoc-2019-week-7-updates/</link><title>GSoC 2019: Week 7 updates</title><description>A long-standing bug was fixed this week. This had been the cause of a test failure in TerasologyLauncherPRs job of our Jenkins, for almost as long as a month. Also did a few tweaks on the Package Manager API, along with a diagram for my initial plan. </description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://www.praj.in/posts/2019/gsoc-2019-week-6-updates/</guid><link>https://www.praj.in/posts/2019/gsoc-2019-week-6-updates/</link><title>GSoC 2019: Week 6 updates</title><description>This week was devoted to design and development of the new package manager, another flagship feature for the Launcher's upcoming release.</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://www.praj.in/posts/2019/gsoc-2019-week-5-updates/</guid><link>https://www.praj.in/posts/2019/gsoc-2019-week-5-updates/</link><title>GSoC 2019: Week 5 updates</title><description>The first phase of GSoC came to an end with a month full of awesome experiences. This last week of June had seen works on the new, dedicated project for producing customized runtime for bundling along with the launcher. </description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://www.praj.in/posts/2019/gsoc-2019-week-4-updates/</guid><link>https://www.praj.in/posts/2019/gsoc-2019-week-4-updates/</link><title>GSoC 2019: Week 4 updates</title><description>A much-anticipated feature was successfully implemented this week - bundled JRE. Gradle now automatically bundles any given JRE with the generated application package. </description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://www.praj.in/posts/2019/gsoc-2019-week-3-updates/</guid><link>https://www.praj.in/posts/2019/gsoc-2019-week-3-updates/</link><title>GSoC 2019: Week 3 updates</title><description>Whew! Probably got the highest number of crashes this week. 😅 I tried to do too many changes in the launcher's initialization phase got the code jumbled up, the main reason for my headache. </description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://www.praj.in/posts/2019/gsoc-2019-week-2-updates/</guid><link>https://www.praj.in/posts/2019/gsoc-2019-week-2-updates/</link><title>GSoC 2019: Week 2 updates</title><description>This week mostly involved studies and work for the Server Manager. On a new branch, I have started replacing the old UI code. Probably at the end of this summer, it'll get merged into develop branch, when the launcher will be on the verge of version 4. </description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://www.praj.in/posts/2019/gsoc-2019-week-1-updates/</guid><link>https://www.praj.in/posts/2019/gsoc-2019-week-1-updates/</link><title>GSoC 2019: Week 1 updates</title><description>The first week of coding came to an end. This month's target is to implement a Server manager and a Game manager. I did spend a good amount of time preparing and learning more about the tools that can come handy. Besides that, a whole new base layout is ready for the launcher's UI. </description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://www.praj.in/posts/2019/introduction-to-terasology-launcher/</guid><link>https://www.praj.in/posts/2019/introduction-to-terasology-launcher/</link><title>Introduction to Terasology Launcher</title><description>This summer I'll be working on Terasology Launcher, the official launcher for the Terasology project. It helps in managing various game versions and configuring local storage, memory settings, and logging level. My project aims to enhance the launcher and make it easier to use. All the progress will be showcased in the upcoming version 4.0. </description><pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2019 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://www.praj.in/posts/2019/starting-my-summer-with-gsoc-2019/</guid><link>https://www.praj.in/posts/2019/starting-my-summer-with-gsoc-2019/</link><title>Starting my summer with GSoC 2019</title><description>It was probably the first time I received some Google-branded emails other than Google Forms stuff. May 7 was a day of celebration, kickstarting my journey into the open source world. Special thanks to Terasology and all my mentors. </description><pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2019 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate></item></channel></rss>